read.me

# Smart Stationary Management System

**Name:** Pranav Pandey  
**Roll No.:** 2301010094

---

## Project Description

The **Smart Stationary Management System** is a project aimed at efficiently managing stationary inventories. It allows users to add new items, update existing stock, delete items, and view the complete inventory list. This system is particularly useful for schools, offices, and stationary shops that require a smart way to track and manage their supplies.

---

## How to Execute the Program

1. **Download the Project Files:**
   - Ensure all necessary source code files are saved locally.

2. **Open the Project:**
   - Use any suitable IDE or an online compiler depending on the programming language used (e.g., Python, C++, Java).

3. **Install Dependencies (if applicable):**
   - If there is a `requirements.txt` file or external libraries needed, install them using:
     ```
     pip install -r requirements.txt
     ```

4. **Run the Program:**
   - Use the terminal or IDE run button.
   - Example for Python:
     ```
     python main.py
     ```
   - Replace `main.py` with the actual main script file name.

5. **Interact with the Application:**
   - Follow the menu options to manage the inventory such as adding new stationary items, viewing the inventory, updating stock, or deleting items.

---

> **Note:** Make sure your environment is set up correctly according to the project requirements.

---

Thank you for using the Smart Stationary Management System!

